# SIMIN ANARAKI

Please visit portfolio at: www.simin.uk

Great Yarmouth, NR31 0HD

(+44) 07818161573

 $\times$ 

Simin.Anaraki@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/Simin-Anaraki

## **ABOUT ME**



I am a computer engineer with over 6 years' experience in the IT industry and finally managed to undertake training to become a developer which I am very passionate about. I have consistently demonstrated a commitment to excellence, a passion for technology, and a relentless drive for self-improvement, which led me to embarking on an exciting transition into the realm of web development, aligning with my profound interest in the digital landscape. This transformation coincided with my relocation to the United Kingdom in February 2022, adding a global dimension to my expertise. I have acquiring skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Sass, and Bootstrap which is essential when working as a junior front-end developer. I am now looking to use my skills and experiences to gain a rewarding job role, where I learn and develop to help me within my career.

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**



#### **Full time student**

**Coding Bootcamp** 

03/2023 - Present

- Studied Front-End Developer
- Programmed and developed websites to build a portfolio.
- · Actively attended multiple seminars and conference to build up knowledge and experience

## **IT Coordinator / Sales**

**KDT** 

05/2019 - 08/2021

#### Tehran Iran - www.kdt.ir

- Applied various sales techniques to steadily expand customer bases.
- Used active listening and relationship-building skills to assess customer needs, build rapport and deliver viable solutions.
- Highlighted product features in line with customer needs, securing high-value sales.
- Used active listening and relationship-building techniques to assess customer needs and deliver viable solutions.
- Maximized sales revenue through effective upselling of associated products.
- Handled concerns and complaints with compassion and care, delivering positive outcomes for continued customer loyalty.

#### **Hardware IT Technician**

**ASUS** warranty service

05/2015 - 03/2019

## **Tehran Iran**

- Executed well-informed critical decision making in high-pressure situations.
- Observed manuals and instructions to effectively install and troubleshoot devices.
- Analyzed failure modes in line with Failure Mode & Effects Analysis (FMEA) framework to tackle recurring faults.
- Planned, scheduled, and delegated daily tasks, consistently meeting demands on technical support teams.
- Supported internal audits and developed corrective actions.
- Conducted tests and inspections to QA/QC standards.
- Regularly monitored and tested equipment performance, implementing preventative maintenance for enhanced functionality.

### **EDUCATION**



- ✓ Science and Culture University Tehran, Iran Bachelor of Computer technology, 2012
- ✓ Asd Junior Front-End Developer Coding Bootcamp Coding Front 2023

## **Technical Skills**

- ✓ HTML
- ✓ CSS
- ✓ JavaScript
- ✓ React
- ✓ Sass
- ✓ Bootstrap
- ✓ Git

I'm holding professional diplomas for these bullet points as well.

## **Other Skills**

- Quality Control
- Assembly process
- ✓ Manufacturing
- ✓ Organizational skills
- ✓ Issue analysis
- ✓ Reporting
- ✓ Team Player
- ✓ Problem Solving
- ✓ Detail oriented
- ✓ Communication skills
- ✓ Strong work ethic
- ✓ Hard worker

## **Hobbies and Interests**

- ✓ Watching Movies
- ✓ Listening to music
- ✓ Programming
- ✓ Exercise and
- ✓ Crafting with wood